‎Netflix 原创动漫电影
‎曾有一位贵族
♪ There once was a lord ♪
‎进入幽暗森林
♪ In dark woods ♪
‎一条奇怪的银色手带
♪ Wearing a strange silver band ♪
‎佩戴手腕上
♪ Around his hand ♪
‎这条手带镶嵌着星矿
♪ The band was charmed With ore from stars ♪
‎令所有怪物退却
♪ Bidding all monsters away ♪
‎退却
♪ Away ♪
‎在那个安静夜晚
♪ On that quiet eve ♪
‎在这些树木之间
♪ Among these trees ♪
‎一个强盗杀害了贵族
♪ A bandit slew the good lord ♪
‎从那死人的手上
♪ Stealing that band ♪
‎偷走了那条手带
♪ Off a dead man's hand ♪
‎因为强盗也害怕
♪ For the bandit also feared ♪
‎怪物
♪ Monsters ♪
‎苏格 给我打起精神来！
Sugo, keep your eyes and ears open!
‎把女孩们都吓到了
It's frightening the girls.
‎要不是你迷路 她们也不会这么害怕
- They wouldn't even be scared…if you hadn't gotten lost.
‎说真的 爸爸 你可是在科德温长大的
Really, Papa, you grew up in Kaedwen.
‎显然是国王开了新路
King clearly dug new trails.
‎是真的吗 爸爸？
Is it true, Papa?
‎强盗会在这些小路上 ‎杀害无辜的人吗？
Are bandits killing innocents along these trails?
‎宝贝
Oh, pumpkin.
‎这里没有强盗
There are no bandits.
‎不！
No!
‎妹妹！
-Sister! -
‎猎魔人
A witcher.
‎看起来挺唬人
Fancy look.
‎你在德鲁伊的祭典上 ‎肯定会有不少收获吧
You must make a killing at druid festivals.
‎这里通常也看不到你们这种东西
Don't usually see your sorts around these parts.
‎原来如此
-Ha! I see. -
‎你是个开路人 想要引领新浪潮
You're a trailblazer, flaunting the new fad.
‎还挺潮呢
Trendsetter, you.
‎胆子真大
-Very bold!
‎哇哦 说真的 大家应该更亲近一些
Whoa, there. People should get acquainted more, really.
‎聊聊天 来点前戏吧
Converse, a little foreplay.
‎尤其是互相即将大开杀戒时
Especially when one's about to kill the other.
‎不过你们鹿首精不会说话 ‎这就麻烦了
Though you leshens don't speak, so there's the rub.
‎森林流浪者 还是致命扑翼蝙蝠群
Forest hobo or deadly, flapping swarm.
‎选好一套外貌
Let's pick a look…
‎就不要再变了
…and stick with it.
‎看来选中了致命扑翼蝙蝠群
Deadly, flapping swarm it is.
‎走开 它还没死
Away. It's not dead.
‎那就杀了它 你是个猎魔人
So kill it. You're a witcher.
‎杀死鹿首精的方法有很多种
There are several ways to kill a leshen.
‎斩首 牺牲几只毛茸茸的动物
Behead it, sacrifice a few of its furry pets,
‎哪怕用几个古老的树精咒也行
even a few old dryad spells will do.
‎你想用哪种…
Which will you…
‎伊格尼法印
Igni
‎格列安巴哈耶艾普梅瓦侯艾林纳斯
Garean bhaedh aip me vhoelynath.
‎你不是说他们不会说话吗？
Thought you said they don't speak?
‎格列安巴哈耶艾普梅瓦侯艾林纳斯
Garean bhaedh aip me vhoelynath.
‎它们是不会说话啊
They don't.
‎等等！
Wait!
‎等等 我是贵族
Wait. I'm noble blood.
‎你不能把我丢在这里
You can't leave me here.
‎我要怎么办？
What am I to do?
‎他说：“练习下悲伤的表情
He said, "Practice your sad face,
‎也许路人会送你一程”
and maybe a passerby will offer you a ride."
‎那你的姐妹们呢？
And what of your sisters?
‎猎魔人说在市长面前 ‎我也要露出这副悲伤的表情
The witcher said to use my sad face on the alderman too.
‎这样 他才会派人
So he'd spare some men to…
‎去收拾尸体
gather the bodies.
‎擦干眼泪 孩子
Dry eyes, child.
‎我会把你的父亲和姐妹们还给你
I'll see that your father and sisters are returned to you
‎让他们体面地安息
and laid to rest properly.
‎苏格的父亲是议会的重要成员
Sugo's father was a treasured member of the Assembly
‎也是国王的忠臣
and a loyal subject to our king.
‎我和弟子们要重新提交请愿书
My students and I resubmit our petition.
‎拿下凯尔•莫罕的猎魔人之家
Seize the witcher home of Kaer Morhen
‎驱逐那里迫害科德温人民的居住者
and exile its occupants for crimes against Kaedwen's people.
‎从这个男孩说的话来看 陛下
From what the boy told us, Your Highness,
‎那个猎魔人斩杀了 ‎危害我们森林的鹿首精
the witcher slew the leshen that was terrorizing our forests.
‎泽布斯特夫人 ‎鹿首精什么时候在科德温作威作福了
Lady Zerbst, since when have leshens prowled about Kaedwen,
‎更别提还如此有敌意？
never mind with such hostility?
‎你的意思是 ‎这些森林袭击案是猎魔人谋划的
Oh, you're suggesting the witchers have been staging these forest attacks.
‎太令人震惊了 吉尔克雷斯特夫人
So scandalous, Madam Gilcrest.
‎怪物种类已经减少了很多
Monster species have dwindled under their swords.
‎猎魔人们需要钱
-They need coin.
‎他们中有些人去做了雇佣兵 ‎有些人则去犯罪
Some have turned to mercenary work, others criminality.
‎有一个甚至拿下了某个奸夫的脑袋 ‎去换取赏金
One even took a bounty on a cheating husband's head.
‎你有证据能证明你口中的阴谋吗？
And you have evidence to prove your conspiracy?
‎还是我们只能靠你神奇的直觉？
Or are we to merely bank on your magical intuition?
‎这是他们的本性 夫人
It's their natures, my lady.
‎猎魔人是邪恶巫术的传承人
Witchers are the offspring of foul sorcery.
‎游荡在我们的土地上
Roaming our lands,
‎被公认为邪恶的骚扰者
voting themselves the stalkers of evil,
‎从容易受骗的人那里骗取钱财
extorting coin from the gullible.
‎诚实又淳朴的农民 ‎却将所有的不幸都归咎于咒语和怪物
Honest, simple peasants who ascribe all misfortune to spells and monsters.
‎术士创造了猎魔人
Mages create the witcher.
‎然后指望我们
Then presume it's our duty to
‎提起水桶 给他们擦屁股
hold the bucket and mop up their brown mess.
‎我赞同泽布斯特夫人的意见
I'm with Lady Zerbst on this one.
‎那些猎魔人应该留在凯尔•莫罕
The witchers remain at Kaer Morhen.
‎除非有什么证据
At least until such time as evidence is provided
‎能够证明你的观点
that supports your theory.
‎猎魔人让别人痛苦的时候
When a witcher inflicts pain,
‎自己会感到狂喜
he experiences ecstasy.
‎那些生物会说上古语
The creature's words are Ellyon.
‎一种已经消失的精灵方言 ‎和暗黑时刻有关
A dead elven dialect linked to darker times.
‎很少有人记得这种古老的语言 ‎更没有什么人敢说
Few remember the ancient tongue. Fewer dare speak it.
‎但是 一个鹿首精怎么会知道
But how a leshen would know it
‎还会害怕什么老巢…
or be afraid of some den--
‎我从没说过害怕
Never said it was afraid.
‎你会说上古语吧 是不是 ‎菲拉凡德芮？
You speak Ellyon, don't you, Filavandrel?
‎你们这些猎魔人就想着钱
You witchers are desperate for coin.
‎找精灵讨工作
Turning to elves for leads on work.
‎这些享受总要花钱的
These pleasures do not pay for themselves.
‎鹿首精怎么说？
What did the leshen say?
‎“小心我的死亡老巢”
"Beware the den of my dead."
‎这是你不想在洗澡时听到的东西
Hmm. Things you don't wish to hear in a bath.
‎你注意到其他不对劲的地方了吗？
Did you notice anything else unusual?
‎树林里有一种能量
There was an energy in the woods.
‎也许是某种魔法
Some sort of magic, maybe.
‎控制了鹿首精 迷惑了它
Controlling the leshen, bewitching it.
‎你这是什么表情？
What's your face?
‎在过去四年的夏天里
Over the last four summers,
‎我们族群的女孩一直在消失
girls have been disappearing from our ranks.
‎天啊 别提精灵的那些事
Oh, God, no elf drama.
‎上一次清洗之后 ‎最开始我们只是害怕会被抛弃
The first we feared were deserting us after the last cleansing.
‎但是 消失的现象一直在发生
-But the disappearances haven't stopped.
‎悲剧 真的 非常糟糕
-Tragic, really. Very terrible.
‎最先消失的人是个年轻的术士 ‎叫做小狐
One of the first to vanish was a young mage, Kitsu.
‎她说上古语 我们应该回到那片森林
She spoke Ellyon. We should return to these forests.
‎听着 我是个猎魔人 菲拉
See, I'm a monster hunter, Fil,
‎不是精灵的马仔 更别说还是凶杀案 ‎但还是祝你好运
not an elf wrangler, not even the murderous ones, but good luck.
‎帮朋友一个忙 好吗？
A favor to a friend, then?
‎帮忙和朋友又不会付钱
Favors and friends don't pay bills.
‎还恰恰相反
Quite the opposite.
‎你还真是不要脸
You've really no shame.
‎我的名声在外
I have a reputation
‎干活拿钱 天经地义
and a healthy estimation of my talent's worth.
‎很抱歉 我还想着把你 ‎从凯尔•莫罕的虚度冬季里拯救出来
My apologies for trying to save you from a wasted winter at Kaer Morhen.
‎虚度？
Wasted?
‎我在这里喝酒 吃饭 睡觉
Well, there's drinking, eating, sleeping.
‎全部免费
All free.
‎还要训练一群贪婪的年轻驱魔人
And the training of another greedy gang of young witchers.
‎这活儿留给我的同伴
I leave that to my peers.
‎想象一下如果你们猎魔人们 ‎不只是为了找刺激和赚钱而干活
Imagine if you witchers labored for more than just thrill and coin.
‎想象一下如果你们的精灵 ‎能像指责别人一样
Imagine if you elves wielded your swords
‎挥舞起自己的剑
-as well as you do guilt. -
‎拜托！搞定它们！
Please! Get them!
‎维瑟米尔 到这里来！
Vesemir, get over here!
‎它们必须离开！
Where do…Hey! They must go!
‎现在它们在小口地咬 不！
Now they're nibbling. No!
‎舔 它们在舔我
Licking. Ooh! They're licking.
‎舌头！
- Oh! Tongues! -
‎快点！
hurry up
‎-不！ ‎-维瑟米尔！
- No! Aah! -Vesemir!
‎不！
No!
‎我让你打的是双结！
I told you, double knots!
‎我打了 父亲 就像你展示的那样
-I did, Father. Just as you showed. -
‎孩子去拿条湿毛巾吧
Let's see if the boy can handle fetching a wet cloth.
‎换成别人会把你儿子卖掉
A lesser man would sell your boy to another family.
‎是的 先生
Yes, sir.
‎至少我儿子证明了您的慷慨
At least my son proves a measure of your generous character.
‎去市场吧 ‎我们需要蓝色树胶来镇定夫人
Head to the market. We will need blue gum to sedate our lady.
‎-不！ ‎-别搞砸了
- No! -Try not to cock it up.
‎请住手！请停手吧！
Please stop! Please make it stop!
‎不！
- No. - No!
‎别动来动去了！
Stop fidgeting!
‎可怜的伊利亚娜 我甚至都不用出手
Poor Illyana. I didn't even have to take a shot.
‎白痴！你差点就杀了我
Moron! You could've killed me.
‎你是来烦我的吗？
Here to bother me?
‎贵族坚持要我去市场上看着你
The Lord insisted I look after you in the market.
‎看起来相当生气
Seemed rather pissed.
‎整天都使唤我们 冲我们大叫
We slave away all day long, getting shout at,
‎唯一给我们的钱 ‎就是让我们拿着钱去买东西
and the only coin we get is when we're sent to fetch them goods.
‎开心点 至少头顶上有个遮挡 ‎肚子没饿着
Just be happy you have a roof over your head and your belly's not empty.
‎勉强遮挡 勉强不饿 ‎勉强能让我们在这里呼吸
Barely a roof, barely not empty. Just enough to keep us here breathing.
‎好吧
- Fine.
‎世界就在那里
There's the world.
‎假如你有很多钱 你最想要买什么？
What would you buy if you had all its coin?
‎我会离开这个村子 环游大陆
I would get the hell out of this village and travel the continent.
‎-冒险？ ‎-当然
-Adventure? -Of course.
‎-荣耀？ ‎-对了
-Glory? -Oh, yes!
‎找姑娘？
Girls?
‎我会买一间漂亮的湖边小屋
I'd buy a gorgeous lake house.
‎我英俊的丈夫和我会在水边 ‎野餐 喝酒
My handsome husband and I would picnic and drink wine by the water
‎我们的孩子在附近玩着抛接游戏
as our children played jacks nearby.
‎你知道我们该怎么做吗？
You know what we should do?
‎拿这个钱去买蜂蜜蛋糕
We should take this coin and buy honey cake.
‎那怎么给夫人买药？
And how will our lady get her herbs?
‎住手！小偷！
Stop! Thief!
‎嘿！
-Hey! -
‎这边！
This way!
‎拦住他！
-Oh! - Stop him!
‎疯子
Nutcase.
‎给我留点！
Save some for me!
‎你看 管用了吧
See, it worked.
‎我就知道如此
I knew it would.
‎在尼弗迦德
In Nilfgaard,
‎人们会把小偷的手给剁掉
they'd cut your thieving hands right off.
‎让你挂在脖子上示众数周
Make you wear 'em round your neck for weeks.
‎聪明的把戏
Smart trick.
‎奇怪的战利品
Odd loot.
‎谁生病了？
Who you got who's sick?
‎和我这样的男人在小巷里 ‎一个女孩还敢这样做？
Where'd a girl find balls like that in an alley wi' a man like me?
‎这是我从那些臭坏蛋那里偷来的
I steal them from smelly cowards
‎他们想要欺负年轻的小姐们
who try to bully young ladies.
‎你是谁？
Who are you?
‎一个慈善家
A humanitarian,
‎恰好听说了有一位本地的夫人
whose well-meaning ears have heard of a local lady
‎失心疯 还发烧了
-lost to madness and fever…
‎看到了不存在的恐怖画面
seeing horrors that aren't really there.
‎蓝色树胶当然会缓解痛苦 但是…
That blue gum will certainly ease the affliction, but, uh…
‎剑才能治愈它
a sword would kill it.
‎我叫戴格兰
Name's Deglan.
‎你们带我去见夫人吧
And you're gonna take me to your noblewoman.
‎否则我就把你们两个害虫 ‎送回市场上去
Or I'm taking you two pests back to the market.
‎恶魔缠上了这个女人
A demon plagues this woman.
‎一个梦魔
A mahr.
‎让你陷入可怕的幻觉 ‎以你的疯狂为食
Puts you down with horrid delusions and feeds off your madness.
‎流星矿石会破坏恶魔的魔法
Meteorite ore disrupts the demon's magic,
‎这样它就可以
so it can be…
‎被去除
removed.
‎出去 现在
Out. Now.
‎所有人都出去
All of you.
‎我想留下
I'd like to remain.
‎你儿子这个年纪 ‎应该见过一两个怪物 对吧？
Your boy's likely seen a monster or two in his time, no?
‎我来施咒
-Oof! - I'll be casting the spell.
‎抓住它就靠你了
- -It's on you to catch the critter.
‎但我以为猎魔人会杀死怪物？
But I thought a witcher slays monsters?
‎杀死野兽
To slay a beast,
‎首先要去理解它
you've first got to understand it.
‎研究它
-Study it.
‎找到它的弱点
Find its weakness.
‎我想让这个玩意活着 刺激一下
I want this sucker alive and kicking.
‎如果可以的话
If possible.
‎稳住了 小伙子
Steady, young fella.
‎就这样还说想留下
And he asked to stay.
‎别让它们进了你的脑子
Never let 'em get in your head.
‎死了比逃了要好
Better dead than fled.
‎总会出现新的怪物
There'll always be another monster.
‎维瑟米尔
Vesemir.
‎去拿点温水来
Fetch warm water.
‎我的头…
My head…
‎我的头好痛
Oh, my head hurts wildly.
‎钱不少 对吧？
Nice weight, isn't it?
‎你觉得你那个混蛋主人 ‎为这事花了多少钱？
How much you suppose the job cost that prick master of yours?
‎恐惧和无知是桩好买卖
Fear and ignorance are good business.
‎赏你的 小伙计
For your service, young fella.
‎带我一起走吧
Take me with you.
‎没什么男孩想当猎魔人
Not many boys seek to be witchers.
‎想端尿送水的人更少
Even fewer seek a life of fetching bedpans and water.
‎那个女孩呢？
And the girl?
‎你的蓝眼睛姑娘呢？
Your blue-eyed lass?
‎你对那个梦魔也犹豫了
You hesitated back with the mahr too.
‎猎魔人不能犹豫
Witchers do not hesitate.
‎-住手吧 ‎-你还想好好过日子吗？
-Stop! -Are you going to enjoy the day?
‎还是仍然因为那个大胆的除魔夜 ‎而感到震惊呢？
Or are you still too shook from your daring night of monster-slaying?
‎那是你的第一次 维瑟米尔
It was your first time, Vesemir.
‎不好意思 比起伺候别人 ‎我想要做点其他有用的事情
Excuse me for wanting to be good at something other than serving.
‎我现在有画面了
Oh, I can see it now.
‎你穿着战斗的盔甲
You, adorned in battle armor,
‎配着银钢剑
steel and silver swords,
‎从奇奇摩、食尸鬼和疯狂的巫师手上 ‎拯救大陆
saving the continent from kikamores, ghouls, and mad sorcerers.
‎邪恶势力会颤抖
Evil would tremble.
‎-对了 是时髦的盔甲 ‎-随你怎么想象都行
-Stylish armor, by the way. -Imagine it however you like.
‎像我们这样的人活下来的唯一办法 ‎就是把自己想成别人
Only way people like us survive is to dream of ourselves as something else.
‎谁知道呢？ ‎也许有一天我会成为能控制雪的公主
Who knows? Perhaps someday I'll be a princess who commands the snow.
‎维瑟米尔 我只是开玩笑
Vesemir, I was only jesting.
‎你觉得我们的命运好笑吗？
You find our fates funny?
‎我为什么要像父亲一样听话和贫穷？ ‎你又为什么要像你妈妈？
Why should I be meek and penniless like my father? Or you like your mother?
‎-你怎么变得这么傻？ ‎-你不会明白的
-What's got you so silly? -You wouldn't understand.
‎维瑟米尔 出去了 我们一无是处
Vesemir, out there, we're nothing.
‎什么也不是
Less than nothing.
‎至少在这里 在庄园里 ‎我们还能安顿下来
At least here, at the estate, we have station.
‎如果我能照顾你呢？
And if I could take care of you?
‎猎魔人昨晚挣的钱
The coin that witcher made last night,
‎你真该看一看
you should've saw it.
‎我会给你买湖边小屋
I'd get you your lake house,
‎所有的酒
all your wine.
‎什么都可以
Anything and everything.
‎都给你
Yours.
‎所以把我欠主人的债变成
So trade my debt to a master I hate
‎欠爱人的债吗？
with a debt to one that I love?
‎等等 伊利亚娜
Wait, Illyana!
‎留下！
Stay!
‎你留下吧
You stay.
‎维瑟米尔大人
Lord Vesemir,
‎我的新好友
my new best friend.
‎我在来的路上遇到了一只鹿首精
Crossed a leshen on my way here.
‎我们听说了
So we've heard.
‎与此同时 我今年赚的钱
Meanwhile, I barely made enough this year
‎都付不起一个硬不起来的男妓
to score a night with a limp-pricked man-whore.
‎你的困境真叫我心碎啊 卢卡
Your woes break me, Luka.
‎然后斯温来了 带了些新人过来
Then we've got Sven here bringing back new recruits.
‎没有买卖开张去杀死怪物
Bad enough we're putting ourselves out of business
‎就够惨了
with every monster we kill.
‎现在同类还多了起来
Now there'll be even more of us.
‎人们生孩子比生钱要多 ‎又不是我的错
Not my fault people make more kids than coin.
‎还有
Also,
‎还不如男妓？
short a man-whore?
‎那你去死吧
Go fuck yourself.
‎你不是什么都“不如”吗？
Aren't you "short" everything?
‎伙计们 怪物在冬天会交配
Boys, monsters will fuck through the winter,
‎春天来了 ‎从这里到那赛尔都会有活儿
then come spring, there'll be jobs from here to Nazair.
‎在那之前 要我说 就玩起来
Until then, I say we perk up,
‎喝起来
drink up,
‎你们俩负责把这些小屁孩 ‎领进猎魔人的世界
and you two focus on breaking these brats into the world of witchering.
‎“猎魔人是没有美德的流氓”
"Witchers are rogues without virtue."
‎“真正魔鬼般的生物 只为杀戮而生”
"True diabolical creatures, fit only for killing."
‎“他们之中 断无好人“
"There is no place amidst honest men for them."
‎我的天 你怎么找到这垃圾的？
My, my. How do you find this rubbish?
‎有几个男孩在回来的路上 ‎看到镇上贴了这些
A few of the boys spotted 'em posted about towns on their way back.
‎“泰特拉•吉尔克雷斯特” ‎听起来像个植物学家
"Tetra Gilcrest." Sounds like a botanist.
‎纯粹主义者
A purist.
‎说什么是第一个人类术士的后代
Rambles about being a descendant of the first human mage.
‎把那个小男孩的姐妹们儿埋了 ‎就那么让你烦恼吗？
Would it have vexed you to bury that lad's sisters?
‎你这是给吉尔克雷斯特那样的混蛋 ‎留下口舌
You're feeding fodder to arses like Gilcrest.
‎那是翼龙齿 不是石化蜥蜴
That's a wyvern tooth, not a basilisk.
‎我看心情 想怎么搭就怎么配
I'll mix and match as I please.
‎听着
Look.
‎-你了解我和孩子们的 ‎-别闹了 年轻人
-You know me and children. -Get over it, young fella.
‎你要教新人击剑
'Cause you're teaching fencing to the recruits.
‎-我这是在受罚吗？ ‎-我今年冬天少了二十多个驱魔人
- Am I being punished? -I'm down two dozen witchers this winter.
‎无能的人都找到了 ‎其他更有利可图的破活儿
Wimps found employ in other more lucrative nonsense.
‎所以我们都要多加把劲
So we'll all be slogging more weight.
‎这个冬天真好 ‎充满了被抛弃的小悲剧
A wonderful winter of abandoned little tragedies.
‎很好
Lovely.
‎现在说鹿首精
Now, this leshen.
‎你肯定觉得那东西被迷惑了
Tell me you've considered the thing was bewitched.
‎我又不是笨蛋
I'm not a dullard.
‎那可不是件容易事
A croon could pull that feat.
‎绝对是更高级的吸血鬼
A higher vampire, definitely.
‎也可能是一种新的鹿首精
Or it could be a new breed of leshen.
‎其实只是精灵们想要玩弄 ‎那种扮演受害者的老把戏
Actually, just elves airing their usual dirty trousers of victimhood.
‎真可惜
Shame.
‎来几个新的野兽对生意有好处
A few new beasts would be…good for business.
‎为什么猎魔人不处理这些？
Why'd the witcher not handle this?
‎谎言和阴谋
- Lies and conspiracy.
‎别看这些脸
- Look away from the faces.
‎我听说鹿首精被杀了
I'd heard the leshen'd been killed.
‎石化蜥蜴出一口气 ‎就能杀死十个强壮的男人
A whiff of basilisk breath could snuff out ten strong men.
‎你找到那东西的尸体了吗？
Did you find the creature's body?
‎猎魔人得有证据才能赚钱
A witcher would need proof to collect his coin.
‎但是…
And yet…
‎至少帮我说服国王
At least help me persuade the king
‎派一个使者去凯尔•莫罕调查
to send an envoy to Kaer Morhen to investigate, please.
‎你的追随者们已经造成了人们的恐惧
Your acolytes have played to people's fears well enough.
‎哪怕只是派出使者的小事 ‎也会像是在指控猎魔人
The mere act of sending an envoy would indict the witchers,
‎还管它什么真相不真相
whatever the truth.
‎你知道成为一个猎魔人要做什么吗？
Do you know what's involved in making a witcher?
‎他们怎样吓唬那些新人？
The horrors done to their recruits?
‎那些男孩比你这里的孤儿大不了多少
-Boys no older than your orphans here. -
‎你死去的丈夫会理解这个的
Your late husband would've understood this.
‎我曾是泽布斯特大人的忠实崇拜者
I was an ardent admirer of Lord Zerbst.
‎他很开明
He was open-minded.
‎有远见
Forward-thinking.
‎毕竟跟你结婚了
Married you, after all.
‎说话小心点
Careful,
‎泰特拉
Tetra.
‎要不然就闭嘴
Or be quiet.
‎科德温的法律 ‎允许遗孀继承丈夫在王庭的位置
Kaedwen's laws grant a widow her husband's seat at court.
‎法律并没有说要抹去她曾经的样子
The laws say nothing about erasing what she once was.
‎太幸运了 夫人
Well, how fortunate, my lady,
‎几乎没有人想打压这件事
that few have wished to press the issue.
‎你好几天都没给我们吃的了！
You ain't fed us in days!
‎我们也没时间睡觉 几乎都站不起来
We ain't given sleep, can barely stand up.
‎现在你还让我们练剑？
Now you got us playing with swords?
‎我和你们一样 不想呆在这里
I don't wish to be here any more than you do.
‎我来大胆猜一猜
I'll hazard a guess.
‎你们都觉得自己出去了的命运 ‎会比在这里更好
You all imagine there are better fates for you out there in the world.
‎但是出去之后
But out there,
‎你们一无所有
you have nothing.
‎但在这里 我们还教会你们 ‎什么是力量
But here, we offer strength.
‎目的
-Purpose.
‎尊重
Respect.
‎以及在外面遇到极大危险时 ‎一线求生的可能
A chance at surviving the very horrors waiting out there.
‎如果你们不想要那样 那这个…
If you don't want that, then this…
‎就浪费了
is wasted on you.
‎“如果你们不想要那样
"And if you don't want that,
‎那这个就浪费了”
then this is wasted on ya."
‎那个大傻子满嘴放屁
Ugh. That dorbel's full of shit.
‎戴格兰大人是在为我们游历做准备
Master Deglan's preparing us for the Path.
‎在这里吃苦总比出去好
-Better hardship here than out there. -
‎今晚真冻死了
Oh, there's a freeze tonight.
‎闭上嘴 能睡会儿就睡一会儿吧
Shut up and steal what sleep you can.
‎不用管托马斯
Ah, don't mind Tomas.
‎意外律
Law of Surprise.
‎直到有人上门敲门 ‎他才知道自己属于猎魔人
Didn't know he belonged to the witchers till one came knocking.
‎意外律？
Law of Surprise?
‎只是好听的说话 ‎没钱付给猎魔人时 就把孩子给他们
Fancy name for when you can't pay a witcher. Give 'em your kid.
‎你是被卖掉的 还是自愿的？
Were you sold, or did you volunteer?
‎我的家里人把我甩过来的 ‎跟大多数人一样
Uh, my folks dumped me here. Like most.
‎谁会选择来这个猪圈？
Who chooses to be in this pigsty?
‎别害怕
-Don't be so scared.
‎他们…
-They're…
‎-他们要毒死我们 ‎-谁？
-They're going to poison us. -Who?
‎这里有术士
There are mages here.
‎那些老头
Old ones.
‎培养猎魔人 他们…
Making witchers, they…
‎他们会杀了我们 然后把我们复活
They'll kill us. Then bring us back, but…
‎但是我们就不正常了
we won't be normal.
‎-他们管这个叫做… ‎-青草试炼 我知道
-They call it-- -The Trial of the Grasses. I know.
‎我也很害怕
I get scared too.
‎然后我想：“很快 我就能出去游历了
Then I think, "Soon, I'll be out on the Path,
‎比大多人都厉害 什么都不想要”
stronger than most anyone, wanting for nothing."
‎我就再也不会害怕了
I'll never be scared again.
‎试炼之后 你会变得比正常要厉害 ‎托马斯
You'll come out the Trials better than normal, Tomas.
‎我保证
On my word.
‎-这是… ‎-是维瑟米尔！
-What the…- It's Vesemir!
‎怎么了？我们在哪里？
What's happened? Where are we?
‎安静 我爸以前说过这个地方
Quiet. My pa used to talk about this place.
‎这里是红色沼泽
It's the Red Swamp.
‎被诅咒了
It's cursed.
‎到处都是恶灵和野兽
It's crawling with evil spirits and beasts.
‎狮鹫
Griffins.
‎这是个测试
This is a test.
‎和其他的一样
Like all the others.
‎去游历 ‎猎魔人的第一本能要是活下去
On the Path, a witcher's first instinct is to survive.
‎靠的是智慧 不是剑
It's about wits, not swords.
‎我们跟着月亮走 直到没有危险
We follow the moon until we're clear.
‎如果附近有怪物 你的徽章会…
If there's a monster close, your medallion will--
‎妖灵！
-Wraiths!
‎保持冷静！
- Keep calm!
‎呆在一起！
Stay together!
‎这边
This way.
‎徽章有时候感应到的是怪物
The medallions sometimes sense the bestiary.
‎尤其是一大群的时候
-Especially when it's full.
‎你是他们的人
- You're one of them.
‎托马斯提到的术士 ‎是你们创造了猎魔人
The mages Tomas mentioned who make witchers.
‎你看起来不太老
You don't look ancient.
‎好吧 术士老得很慢
Well, mages age quite slowly.
‎猎魔人也是
Witchers do too.
‎我们都有几十年时间来磨练技能
Gives us both decades to hone our respective skills.
‎但试炼只是我职责的一部分
The Trials are only part of my duty, though. -
‎别害怕
Don't fear.
‎这只是杂交基因的副产品
It's merely a side effect of its hybrid genes.
‎喀拉螂
Krallachs.
‎我在这个标本里 ‎发现了三个不同的物种
I've identified three different species in this specimen's makeup.
‎真是个讨厌的小杂种
-It's a nasty little crossbreed.
‎戴格兰大人说过 ‎怪物不能和其他物种交配
Master Deglan said monsters can't mate with other species.
‎没错
True.
‎但是它们可以被改造
Though they can be engineered.
‎想一下 有一群野兽
Imagine an army of beasts
‎它们被设计出来 ‎就是为了铲除精灵和古老的物种
designed to wipe out the elves and the Old Races
‎保护土地和食物
to secure land and food.
‎炼金术
The alchemy was…
‎已经够不体面的了
inelegant, though.
‎大部分杂种都会立刻死亡
Most crossbreeds died instantly.
‎术士制造怪物
Mages made monsters,
‎然后再制造猎魔人去杀掉它们？
then made witchers to kill them?
‎今天 由我和我的术士守护
Today, my mages and I guard the secrets
‎这些突变炼金术的秘密
to such mutagenic alchemy,
‎以防进一步被滥用
preventing further abuse.
‎对了 我是瑞德里赫
I'm Reidrich, by the way.
‎你是傻了吗 瑞德里赫？
Are you daft, Reidrich?
‎猎魔人应该知道 ‎自己在历史中的位置
A witcher deserves to understand its place in history.
‎在你舔舐伤口的时候 ‎来了一个骑手
A rider came while you were licking your wounds.
‎给你留了封信
Left a letter for ya.
‎你早就知道托马斯和其他人 ‎会死在沼泽吗？
Did you know that Tomas and the others would die in the swamp?
‎这是数字游戏 小伙子
It's a numbers game, young fella.
‎有多少人能在试炼中幸存？
How many survive these Trials?
‎看情况
Depends.
‎有多少人能成为猎魔人？
How many are witchers?
‎信在你的小屋里 现在就读 ‎要不然我就烧掉了
Letter's by your cot. Read it now, before I burn it.
‎“维瑟米尔”
"Vesemir."
‎“你的想法可能和我们相去甚远 ‎所以我会简短点说”
"Your thoughts are likely far from here, so I will be brief."
‎“你的爸爸死了”
"Your father is dead."
‎“科德温占领了我们的村庄 ‎他在帮大人和夫人逃跑时被杀死了
"Kaedwen took our village and he was killed while helping the lord and lady escape,
‎但大人和夫人也都被杀害了”
-both of whom were also slain." -
‎“别回家了 维瑟米尔
- -"Do not return home, Vesemir,
‎这里的一切已经过去了”
if this were ever that to you."
‎“我希望你已经在这个脆弱的世界里 ‎找到温暖和安逸
"I hope you have found warmth and comfort in this brittle world
‎你所在的地方也会对你很好 ‎最重要的是 要公平”
and that the world is being kind to you, and most of all, fair."
‎“我的话 科德温的一户贵族人家 ‎收留了我”
"For me, a noble family from Kaedwen has claimed me theirs."
‎“他们是更和善的主人”
"They are kinder masters."
‎“他们让我画画 教我如何读词 ‎还会写一些”
"They let me paint and show me how to read words, as well as write a few."
‎“我吃得挺好的 很安心”
"I am well-fed and at peace."
‎“这个被烧尽的小镇上 ‎没什么好怀念的了
"There was little to miss in our burnt-out town,
‎我们的雪球仗和小巷甜品 ‎是我沉重的回忆
and our snowball fights and alleyway desserts
‎现在我很高兴地要将它们埋藏起来”
are heavy memories I now happily lay to rest."
‎“去寻找你的重生吧 维瑟米尔”
"Find your rebirth, Vesemir,
‎“摆脱过去的负担和伤害”
free of past burdens and hurts."
‎“对
"And yes,
‎摆脱我”
free of me."
‎“那样最好”
"It is best that way."
‎“好好地生活和爱”
"Live and love well."
‎“伊利亚娜”
"Illyana."
‎（通缉 400 生死都可）
‎对
Right.
‎谁想骑马出去找一个安静的好地方 ‎美美地喝上一杯？
So, who wishes to ride and get blitzed somewhere nice and quiet?
‎我们留下来 看看谁能活下来
We stay and see who survives.
‎那可能要花好几天
That could take days.
‎可能会是艾斯卡尔 兰伯特
It'll be Eskel, Lambert,
‎也可能是雷姆斯
maybe Remus.
‎好了 我们可以去大醉一场吗？
Now, can we please go get right properly drunk?
‎让他们生气吧
Oh, let them sulk.
‎我们去喝酒
We'll drink.
‎我回来要钱的时候 ‎那个助产士差点晕了过去
The midwife almost fainted when I came for my payment.
‎我看起来可怕极了
-I looked an awful terror,
‎血淋淋 黏糊糊的 ‎但是你们懂的
red and sticky,but, you know,
‎那就是工作
that's the job.
‎那吸血妖鸟呢？
And the striga?
‎她治好了吗？
Was she cured?
‎是的 当然
Yes. Yes, of course.
‎下一个故事之前 我们还得加点酒
We need more before the next tale.
‎那个助产士 ‎应该请个更好的救世主
You know, that midwife should've hired a better savior.
‎一个品德高尚的人
A man of virtue and honor.
‎一个真正的男人
A real man.
‎不是变种人
Not a mutant.
‎现在骑士们也在学吸血妖鸟咒语吗？
Are knights being schooled in striga curses now?
‎在哪里开课？ ‎学屈膝礼和马背比武的间歇吗？
Where'd that lesson fit? Between learning curtsy and joust?
‎我们都是来这里喝酒的 ‎找些非暴力的乐子
We're all here for a little drink and non-violent fun.
‎这就是“你的善良”吗？
Is this the "your kind" bit?
‎你吓到了这些人
You frighten these people.
‎当你吓到那个助产士的时候 ‎你是在诈骗
As you frightened that midwife you swindled.
‎你们最好离开
Best you leave.
‎现在就走
Right now.
‎我见过骑士想努力干我们的活
I've seen knights try to do our job.
‎收拾怪物
Tidy up monsters.
‎警示故事 送给各位
Cautionary tales, all of you.
‎尤其是可爱的那些
Especially the cute ones.
‎这两个猎魔人应该受审和处决
The two witchers should be tried and executed.
‎不必问任何问题
No questions asked.
‎愚蠢的我
Silly me.
‎我还以为受审就是要提问呢
Here I thought trials were all about questions.
‎这两个人杀了你的两个警卫 殿下 ‎你就这么放任不管吗？
These two killed two of your guard, Your Highness. You'd let that stand?
‎陛下 酒保说 ‎是您的骑士挑起了争执
Sire, the barkeep claims your knights instigated the altercation.
‎这些猎魔人只是在自保
These witchers were defending themselves.
‎人民对君主的信任 ‎已经因为森林袭击而产生动摇
The people's faith in the monarchy already wavers due to the forest attacks.
‎现在他们会听说国王袖手旁观 ‎不顾两个怪物血刃骑士
Now they'll hear the crown waxed idly as two monsters shed knighted blood.
‎所以我们应该和猎魔人们开战？
So we should go to war with the witchers?
‎只有这样 ‎你才能他们感受到你所害怕的吗？
If only so you can make them what you fear?
‎他们会要人命 ‎我们都同意这一点 泰特拉
They are deadly. On that, we agree, Tetra.
‎这样的战斗会血染科德温
And such a battle would flood Kaedwen red.
‎敬请议会记住 ‎夫人在这里的职位是荣誉性的
The Assembly should remember the lady's seat here is honorary.
‎但这还是我的位置
-Yet it is still my chair.
‎用她的身体赚来的
Earned by her body.
‎不是因为血缘或头衔
Not by blood or title.
‎天啦 安静！
Gods, quiet!
‎我要让骑士们把你们俩都杀了 ‎好图个耳根清静
I'll have my knights kill you both for the sake of my ears.
‎泰特拉说得对 陛下
Tetra's right, actually, sire.
‎你的臣民们期待着有所行动
Your subjects expect action.
‎如果能一举两得怎么样？
What if you act on two fronts with one move?
‎把森林清理干净 ‎还能避免与猎魔人的战争？
Clear out our forests while also avoiding war with the witchers?
‎警卫？
-Guard? -
‎怎么了？
Aye?
‎你听到了吗？
Do you hear that?
‎-像是砰的一声 ‎-喂！
-It's like this pinging noise. -Hey!
‎你想挨打吗
Are you eager for a beating,
‎变种人？
mutant?
‎我愿意买一口小锅来尿尿 ‎再来点像样的面包
I'd settle for a pot to piss in and some halfway decent bread, please.
‎有点大方 但是…
Ah. A bit generous, but…
‎没必要切开
No need to split this one.
‎不用像我们年轻时候那样
Not like when we were younger.
‎我知道猎魔人老得慢 但是
I knew witchers aged differently, but, well,
‎看看你啊！
look at you!
‎伊利亚娜！
Illyana!
‎毫无疑问 你把我想成了个老姑娘 ‎埋头苦干
No doubt you imagined me an old spinster by now, slaving away.
‎如果你有想象过我的话
That is if you ever imagine me at all.
‎你…你的信
Uh… your letter.
‎-你被卖到了一个新的庄园 ‎-是的
-You'd been sold to a new estate. -Yes.
‎科德温的泽布斯特家
The Zerbsts of Kaedwen.
‎他们很和善
They were kind enough, but it…
‎他们的儿子真的很喜欢我
it was their son who was truly fond of me,
‎也不在乎我的身份
despite my station.
‎已经是很久前的事了 ‎你有湖边小屋了吗？
It's been an age. Did you ever get that lake house?
‎湖边小屋？
Lake house?
‎我的天啊 湖边小屋！
Oh, my, the lake house!
‎没有湖 没有
No lake, no.
‎但有个不错的家
But a nice home.
‎我丈夫去世后 我把它变成了孤儿院
Turned it into an orphanage after my husband passed.
‎我们也有孩子 女儿们
We had children too. Girls.
‎很恐怖 三个
Horrors, all three of them.
‎其中有一个让我变成了祖母 ‎我求她不要
One just made me a grandmother. I begged her not to.
‎但她们是固执的小淘气
But they're stubborn little needlers.
‎经常会让我想起你
They often remind me of you--
‎天啊
Oh, gods.
‎我在胡言乱语了
I'm… rambling.
‎你肯定被说烦了
You're bored.
‎不 没问题
No, no, no. You're fine.
‎挺好的
You're good.
‎这有点出乎意料
Uh… this is unexpected, yes.
‎有点新鲜
Little fresh.
‎但是也很可爱
But, uh… also lovely.
‎你有这样完整…
You've had such a full--
‎你想杀死我已经去世的丈夫 ‎把孤儿院烧成平地
You wish to kill my already-dead husband and burn the orphanage to the ground.
‎这不是我想说的话
Not the precise words I'd use.
‎泽布斯特大人对我很好
Lord Zerbst was kind to me.
‎一点也不完美 但是
By no means perfect, but…
‎他离开之后 我会特别想念他
he's someone you miss very much when they depart.
‎但我也听说了你的事迹
The tales I've heard of you, though.
‎受人雇佣 恃强凌弱的猎魔人
The swashbuckling witcher for hire.
‎“屠魔者维瑟米尔
"The slayer Vesemir,
‎专雇用于屠杀最邪恶的生物“
priced only for the foulest of creatures."
‎不久之前 ‎你还在往我脑海里灌输这些
Well, not too long ago, you were stuffing my head full of those very notions.
‎时间对你来说不一样
Years do work differently for you.
‎说起来 时间是什么？
What's time, anyway?
‎一切
-Everything.
‎国王愿意赦免你和你朋友的罪行
The king is willing to grant you and your friend amnesty for your crimes.
‎然后 我要提醒你 ‎我继承了亡夫的职责
Then you are reminded that I carry the duties
‎尊敬的泽布斯特大人 ‎担任了国王的顾问
of my late husband, the noble Lord Zerbst, adviser to the throne.
‎每笔交易都有价格
Every deal has a price.
‎去把阿德•卡莱外面树林里 ‎杀害了我们人民的东西给杀掉
Kill whatever is murdering our people in the woods outside Ard Carraigh.
‎那我的同僚卢卡呢？
And my colleague, Luka?
‎我会照顾他
-He'll have my care.
‎条件合理
-Reasonable terms.
‎你也要有个陪护人
You'll take a chaperone too.
‎那个吧
That, there, well…
‎那个就有了问题
that's a problem.
‎游历相当危险
The Path's quite perilous,
‎你是个女士 夫人
and you are a lady, my lady.
‎而且 不能让你这样的贵族
Also, can't have a noble such as you
‎看到我这样的变种人的不堪之事
seen slumming about with the mutant likes of me.
‎那你肯定会很高兴听到 ‎我不是你的陪护人
Then you'll no doubt be pleased to hear that I am not your chaperone.
‎我可不想做你的向导或者保姆 女巫
I have no intention of playing guide or nurse to you, witch.
‎我才不管你祖上是谁
I don't care who your great-great-whoever was.
‎相信我
On my word,
‎我会杀了这只野兽
I will slay this beast.
‎为了你 伊利亚娜
For you, Illyana.
‎也许根本没有怪物
Might not be a monster at all, either.
‎杀掉你们卡莱尔大人的鹿首精 ‎被施了魔法
The leshen that killed your man Carlisle was bewitched.
‎是一个精灵干的
By an elf.
‎“为什么是精灵？”
- -"Why an elf?"
‎问到点子上了
Ah! Glad you asked.
‎听着 另一个很年长 ‎但是看起来很年轻的精灵
See, another very old but very young-looking elf
‎请我帮他寻找一群暂时消失了的女孩
asked me to help him to find a group of misplaced girls.
‎关键是猎魔是个买卖
Point is, witchering is a business.
‎你必须保住招牌
You have to keep a brand.
‎如果被人知道狠揍了宁芙 帮助精灵 ‎就接不到大买卖了
Can't score the big jobs if you're known for swatting nymphs and helping out elves.
‎火魔法不是被正直的术士禁止了吗？
Isn't fire magic forbidden by upstanding mages?
‎目前只有在极少数术士 ‎能够拥有控制火焰的魔法
Only insofar as there are very few mages blessed with the skill to control the flames.
‎很明显 你很特别
Huh. You're very special, clearly.
‎对你来说 我看起来一定很蠢
I must seem silly to you.
‎但是混沌能量 那…
But Chaos, it's…
‎无法用语言描述
Well, words fail description.
‎猎魔人也和混沌能量有关系
Witchers are connected to Chaos too.
‎只是你们的关系很腐败和堕落
Only your connection is corrupted and corrosive.
‎少了很多谴责
And far less condemning.
‎有一个故事说 ‎猎魔人曾经帮助了一个生病的祭司
There's a story about a witcher who helped an ailing priest.
‎屠魔人相信 ‎这场病其实是一个诅咒
The monster-slayer believed the sickness was, in fact, a curse,
‎可以通过杀掉施咒的人进行解除
and could be lifted by killing whoever placed it.
‎祭司很快想到了一个当地的女巫师
The priest quickly fingered a local sorceress,
‎一个总给他找麻烦的笨女孩
a stupid girl who always caused him trouble.
‎猎魔人杀了她
The witcher killed her,
‎并且拿到了一大笔珠宝
and was rightly paid in gems and jewels.
‎-祭司明显好转了起来 ‎-是的
-The priest obviously got better. -He did.
‎然后过了几天
And then a few days later,
‎他在厨子的东西里 ‎看到了一块美丽的宝石
he found a beautiful gem amid his cook's belongings,
‎就是他给聪明的猎魔人的那一块
identical to the one he'd given the clever witcher.
‎他让厨师给祭司下毒了 ‎让他也参与了其中
Ah. He had the cook poison the priest's meals.Cut him in on the take.
‎聪明的骗局 ‎真希望我也能想到
Smart con. Wish I'd thought of it.
‎正如我所说
As I said…
‎腐败
corrupted.
‎好美
Ah, lovely.
‎-你带着我们绕了一圈 ‎-不是
-You've led us in a circle. -No.
‎我认识这些森林
I know these forests.
‎卡莱尔大人也是
Hmm. So did Lord Carlisle.
‎在艾瑞图萨
At Aretuza,
‎我们用魔法将不好的幻象 ‎投射到不怎么样的食物上
we used magic to cast pleasant illusions around unpleasant foods.
‎让食物更好吃一点
Made food tastier,
‎但是幻觉的余味？
yet the aftertaste of the illusion?
‎真苦
Bitter.
‎混沌能量洁净了我们的心灵
Chaos clear our hearts and minds.
‎让我们看到正确的真实事物
Let our eyes see right and true.
‎揭开蒙蔽我们心智的遮盖物
Lift the shroud that cloaks our mind.-Lift the shroud that cloaks our mind!
‎那个幻觉完美无瑕
That illusion was flawless.
‎维持这样的艺术 需要极大能量
The power needed to maintain such art…
‎完全可以给鹿首精施咒
Could also bewitch a leshen.
‎格列安巴哈耶艾普梅瓦侯艾林纳斯
Garean bhaedh aip me vhoelynath.
‎小狐？
-Kitsu?
‎这是你的朋友？
-Friend of yours?
‎朋友的朋友
Friend of a friend.
‎格列安巴哈耶艾普梅瓦侯艾林纳斯
Garean bhaedh aip me vhoelynath!
‎对 得让我知道你的死亡老巢在哪里 ‎这样我才能避得开
Yes. I'll need to know what and where your den is if I'm to avoid it,
‎特别是你还在为了它而杀人
especially since you're, you know,-slaughtering people over it.
‎猎魔人
-Witcher.
‎我从没见过这样的石化蜥蜴
I've never seen such a species of basilisk.
‎-又是幻觉？ ‎-我们很快就会知道了
-Another illusion? -We'll no doubt find out shortly.
‎我知道 她让每个人都觉得烦
I know. She has that effect on everyone.
‎但还是要有礼貌
But still, manners.
‎不！
No!
‎-是真的 ‎-可能稍微低估了你一点点
-It was real. -Might have slightly underestimated you.
‎一点点
Slightly.
‎小狐 这事情不必升级
Kitsu, this needn't escalate.
‎猎魔人！
Witcher!
‎她的幻象能力是不自然的
Her powers of illusion are unnatural.
‎我遇到的第一个怪物是梦魔
First monster I ever encountered was a mahr.
‎让女人看到并不存在的噩梦 ‎而是幻象
Made a woman see nightmares that weren't really there. Illusions.
‎-小狐是个精灵 ‎-那她为什么闻起来像是梦魔？
-Kitsu's an elf. -Then why does she smell like a mahr?
‎精灵学校
An elven school.
‎以前盛夏时候 ‎他们会把年轻后代送过来
They used to send their young here during high summer.
‎那是你们最后一次大扫荡 ‎将这里改造成要塞之前
Before repurposing it as a garrison during your last cleansing spree.
‎没有血迹
No signs of blood.
‎但我还是能闻到她的味道
I can still smell her, though.
‎是的
Yes.
‎她来过这里
She was here.
‎就在我们的战斗之前
Just before our fight.
‎猎魔人
Witcher!
‎我其实是有名字的 你知道吧
I do have a name, you know.
‎这是怎么了？
What was done to them?
‎她们都是精灵
They're all elves.
‎女精灵
Girls.
‎在这边
Over here.
‎救命
Help.
‎天啦 又欠一份人情
Gods, not another favor.
‎这是谁啊？
Who's this one?
‎我之前提过的朋友
My aforementioned friend.
‎他在找那些女孩
He was searching for those girls.
‎你要是放下对金钱的执念帮我一把 ‎本来可以救下一些命的
And I could've saved some, had you set aside your love of coin and helped.
‎小狐绑架了她们
- Kitsu's been kidnapping them.
‎是的 她在女孩身上做实验
-Yes. Experimenting on the girls.
‎她在用奇怪的炼金术想改变她们
She's using some strange alchemy to try to change them.
‎把她们变成什么？
Change them to what?
‎变成她那样的东西
Into whatever she's become.
‎我跟着她来到这里 想阻止她 ‎但是小狐的能量…
I tracked her here, tried stopping her, but… Kitsu's power…
‎她就让你活下来了？
And she just let you live?
‎我能够理解你不懂我们的想法
I understand if that's a concept unfamiliar to your kind.
‎如果小狐使用巫术 ‎试着改变这些女孩
If Kitsu was using sorcery to try and mutate those girls,
‎那是谁改变了她呢？
who mutated her?
‎她的基因与梦魔的基因拼接起来了
Her genes were spliced with those of a mahr.
‎这也解释了她的超自然力量
It explains her unnatural power.
‎她是个杂种
She's a crossbreed.
‎这怎么可能？
How is such a thing possible?
‎就像他被造出来那样
The same way he was made.
‎突变炼金术
Mutagenic alchemy.
‎只有凯尔•莫罕的术士知道这个秘密
Its secrets known only to mages at Kaer Morhen.
‎你们就是凶手
You're behind all this.
‎太荒谬了
That's ridiculous.
‎猎杀怪物挣钱还不够吗？
-Hunting monsters for coin wasn't enough?
‎现在你们还制造怪物？
Now you make them?
‎猎魔人生活不易 对 但是…
Witchers are struggling, yes, but…
‎真可惜
Shame.
‎来几个新的野兽 对生意有好处
A few new beasts would be…good for business.
‎更多的怪物 更多的活儿 更多的钱
More monsters, more jobs, more coin.
‎又一个厉害的骗局
Another sharp con.
‎我发誓 菲尔 我没有…
-I swear, Fil, I didn't-- -
‎又一个怪物
Another monstrosity.
‎她还是一个精灵
She's still an elf.
‎你看到了这些生物的能力
You saw what these creatures can do.
‎菲尔 哪怕这个女孩的能量 ‎只有小狐的一半
Fil, if the girl has even half Kitsu's power,
‎她也很危险
she's dangerous.
‎这个女巫是不是跟你说了一样的话？
Doesn't this witch say similar of you?
‎我会把她带回我的族群 ‎她会像精灵一样长大
I will take her back to my people. She will be raised as an elf.
‎好一片善心
Charitable.
‎我猜用不了多久 ‎你就会让她来袭击我们
Though I imagine it won't be too long before you sic her on us.
‎你赢了
You won.
‎你打败了我们
You beat us.
‎至少让我们保留一点体面
At least allow us the indignity
‎清理我们族类的丑事 ‎变种人或者其他什么的
of scavenging whatever's left of our kind, mutant or otherwise.
‎当帮朋友一个忙吧
As a favor to a friend.
‎带孩子走吧 现在
Take the child and go. Now.
‎你犯了一个严重的错误
You have made a serious error.
‎如果那个女孩再伤害一个生灵 菲尔…
Should that girl ever harm a single soul, Fil--
‎那我就杀了她
Then I will slay her.
‎静待你和你的剑来找我
Quietly welcome you and your sword.
‎我应该要出些钱的 ‎那你就好处理了
I should've offered up some coin. Then you would've handled matters.
‎这不是钱的问题
It was not a question of price.
‎猎魔人也讲武德？
Oh, the witcher's found his morals?
‎你以为自己很纯洁吗 泰特拉？ ‎没有污点吗？
You think you're so pure, Tetra? Not a blemish?
‎看看外面
Look outside.
‎那就是你的道德
There's your morality.
‎腐败和毁灭都散发着仇恨的臭气
Rot and ruin all reeking of hate.
‎管好你的破事 我会管我自己的
Tend to that filth, and I'll tend to mine.
‎这样不会有好结果的
Nothing good can come of this.
‎恐惧和无知是桩好买卖
Fear and ignorance are good business.
‎戴格兰和我们第一次见面时 ‎就是这么说的
That's what Deglan said the first time we met.
‎现在听好了
Now look.
‎我需要确定一下
I need to know for certain.
‎我想请你跟我一起逃走
I'd ask you to flee with me.
‎我知道你需要做什么
I know what you have to do.
‎我不会让你觉得是你再次抛弃了我
And I won't have you feeling as though you've abandoned me again.
‎我试着阻止过他
- I tried to stop him.
‎但猎魔人们 他们从不犹豫
- -But witchers, they never hesitate.
‎吉尔克雷斯特夫人提供了证据
Madam Gilcrest has given proof.
‎这个人培养了可怕的东西
This one breeds monstrosities,
‎威胁了我的王国
terrorizes my kingdom,
‎欺骗了人民
and swindles the people.
‎你到底在说什么鬼东西？
What the hell are you talking about?
‎陛下 并非所有的猎魔人 ‎都知道这些杂种的存在
Sire, not all witchers were aware of these crossbreeds.
‎泽布斯特夫人 你证明了
Lady Zerbst, you are testament to the perils
‎信任仆人的危险
of trusting a servant.
‎陛下…
Your Highness--
‎如果可以的话 陛下
If it pleases, sire,
‎我想请问一下 ‎吉尔克雷斯特夫人现在在哪里？
might I ask where Madam Gilcrest is now?
‎怪物们已经灭绝了
Monsters were going extinct.
‎我必须保护我们的生活方式
I had to protect our way of life.
‎想想你挣的那些钱 小子
Think of all the coin you stand to make, young fella.
‎-别这样叫我 ‎-你该感激我 小子
-Do not call me that. -Check your gratitude, boy.
‎是你来找我的
You came to me.
‎我可以把你送回去倒尿盆
I could've shipped you right back to those bedpans.
‎你别装作自己不知道当时向我丢钱
Don't pretend you didn't know exactly what you were doing
‎你是有何居心
when you threw me those coins.
‎你早知道我会来
You knew I would come.
‎我们被创造出来 ‎是为了杀掉这些生物
We were created to kill creatures like these,
‎而不是制造它们
not to make them.
‎我不会为自己做了该做的事情而后悔
I won't weep for doing what needed doing.
‎我跟你说过了
I told you.
‎猎魔人从不犹豫
A witcher never hesitates.
‎我知道
Oh, I know.
‎那精灵呢？
What about with the elf?
‎你在改变小狐之前 给她选择了吗？
Did you give Kitsu a choice before you mutated her?
‎没有 我以为我们杀了她
No, I thought we'd killed her.
‎那个突变不太稳定 能量太大了
That mutation was unstable. Too much power.
‎显然 她的死 ‎是她打造出的聪明的幻象之一
Clearly, her death was one of her clever little illusions.
‎这一切都是为了挣钱
All of this to line our pockets.
‎你总是太专注于手中的黄金
You were always too focused on the gold in your hand.
‎你从来没有抬头看过是谁给你钱 ‎看看他们的眼睛
You never looked up to see who's paying you. See their eyes.
‎我们吓坏了他们
We terrify 'em.
‎唯一阻止人类猎杀我们的方法
The only thing keeping men from hunting us
‎是让他们防范那些更可怕的野兽
are the scarier beasts we keep away.
‎人类很快会死
Humans die quick,
‎他们会穷尽一生
so they spend their lives
‎害怕和憎恨
fearing and hating.
‎问问矮人或者你的精灵朋友
Ask the dwarves or your elf friend.
‎人类总是需要怪物的
Men will always need monsters.
‎我们也是
-Now, so do we.
‎我们都是孤儿
-We're all orphans.
‎我们一直都希望你能保护我们
We've always looked to you to protect us.
‎你得把这些烧成灰
You have to burn it to the ground…
‎不然我会烧掉
or I will.
‎我不想跟你打
I don't want to fight you.
‎我们必须自保 维瑟米尔
We've got to protect ourselves, Vesemir.
‎得保护你！
Got to protect you!
‎你们两个想先停下 不要杀掉彼此
If you two would like to stop trying to kill each other,
‎我们有客人来了
we have a visitor.
‎她来了
She's coming.
‎杀死所有猎魔人！
- Away with all witchers!
‎泰特拉没有浪费时间
Tetra wasted no time.
‎消息传得很快
Word spread quickly.
‎不仅在传杂种的事 ‎还说猎魔人在保护精灵
Not only of the crossbreeds, but of witchers protecting elves.
‎卢卡呢？
And Luka?
‎这就是你们两个干的好事
This is your two's doing.
‎他们总会来的 迟早的事情
They were always gonna come, sooner or later.
‎好吧
Well,
‎总有比战斗去死更好的方法
maybe there was a way for us to die the better men.
‎我和我的术士知道 ‎突变炼金术的秘密
My mages and I are the ones who know the secrets to mutagenic alchemy.
‎泰特拉最想要的是我们的脑袋
Tetra will want our heads most.
‎如果我们死了
If we die,
‎那就没有猎魔人了
there can be no more witchers.
‎把你自己关在实验室里
Seal yourselves in your labs.
‎我们剩下的其他人会团结起来 ‎终结她的邪恶小心思
The rest of us will rally and end her little cult.
‎贱人可看不到天亮
Bitch won't see dawn.
‎低估泰特拉 ‎你会变成看不到太阳升起的人
Underestimate Tetra and you'll be the one who's seen their last sunrise.
‎也许她会听得下道理
Perhaps she'll listen to reason.
‎他可能是个混蛋
He may be a bastard…
‎但戴格兰是对的
but Deglan is right.
‎这件事无可避免
This was inevitable.
‎为什么？
Why?
‎因为你们不一样
-Because you're different. -
‎杀人比容忍更容易
And killing is easier than tolerating.
‎我希望你离得越远越好
I want you as far away from this place as possible.
‎这里有孩子
There are children here.
‎-他们受过训练 ‎-孩子 维瑟米尔
-They've been trained. -Children, Vesemir.
‎就像他带走你时的那个年纪
As you were when he took you.
‎我会带着他们去地下室 ‎直到战斗取得胜利
I'll guide them to the cellar until the battle's won.
‎这一次
For once,
‎我会找到自己的位置
I will decide my place.
‎你总是充满劲头
You've always had too much fire.
‎还很美
And beauty.
‎拜托了 我都快70岁了
Please… I'm nearly 70.
‎我也是
So am I.
‎美丽的山顶
Beautiful peaks.
‎对战争来说太纯净了
Too pure for war.
‎快滚回去 ‎把你杀死的那个人的尸体还回来
Scurry off and return with the body of the man you murdered, witch.
‎他之所以被处决 ‎就是因为你们自己捣鼓那些野兽
He was executed in the name of those your homemade beasts butchered.
‎不会再这样了 泰特拉
There'll be no more of them, Tetra.
‎相信我
Upon my word.
‎猎魔人是开价方面的专家
Well, witchers are experts in price.
‎你的话值多少钱 维瑟米尔？
What is the worth of your word, Vesemir?
‎有些东西是
Some things…
‎无价之宝
are beyond cost.
‎那你呢？
And you?
‎你会给我承诺吗？
Do you give me your word?
‎我什么都不会给你
I give you nothing.
‎珍惜这个机会快离开 ‎否则就用你的尸体填满美丽山巅之谷
Save the chance to fill the valleys of our pretty peaks with your corpses.
‎我们是一群猎魔人
We are an army of witchers.
‎你是人类
You are human.
‎小狐
Kitsu.
‎她听说你拆了她的老巢
She was gutted to hear how you sacked her den,
‎毁了她的作品
destroyed her work,
‎谋杀了那个她唯一的孩子后 ‎伤心欲绝
and murdered the girl, her only child.
‎以怪制怪
Monsters to fight monsters.
‎真不像你的前人
How unlike your predecessors.
‎集合！
Rally! Rally!
‎打起精神 我们上！
Steel your nerves, lads. We charge!
‎-放下剑！ ‎-我们没时间犹豫了
- Swords away. Swords away! -We haven't time to hesitate.
‎就信我一次吧！
Just bloody trust me for once!
‎拜托！
Please!
‎猎魔人 听令！
Witchers, on me!
‎现在！
-Now! -
‎冷静
- Be calm. Be calm. -
‎你们安全了
You're safe.
‎必须将猎魔人从地球上抹去
Witchers must be wiped from the surface of this Earth,
‎所有痕迹都要撒满盐和硝石
and all traces strewn with salt and saltpeter.
‎她要去找瑞德里赫！
She's going for Reidrich!
‎我和其他人会负责这座桥 ‎喝了药 把他们的人数减到一半
Me and the others will hold the bridge. Use the drop to halve their numbers.
‎你们两个 拦住她！
You two, stop her!
‎你能原谅我多一会儿吗 小子？
Can you forgive me long enough, young fella?
‎如果她抓到瑞德里赫 我们就完蛋了
If she gets Reidrich, it's the end of us.
‎找到她！
Find her!
‎拦住她！
-Stop her! -
‎粮仓里有个舱口
There's a hatch in the grain hold.
‎可以从后面的小路过去
It lets out on the back pathway.
‎你是怎么知道的？
How do you know this?
‎他本来想着跑路！
He was trying to run away!
‎跑得越远越好
Run as far away as possible.
‎所有人
All of you.
‎除非有人追着脚后跟来了 ‎否则只管跑
Rub the heel raw, to the bone, if you have to.
‎不要停
Don't stop.
‎把剑放下
Lower your swords.
‎这是大屠杀 泰特拉
This is genocide, Tetra.
‎他们是因为你们才培养了那些怪物 ‎这里没有纯洁
They bred those monsters because of you. There is no purity here.
‎只是恐惧和仇恨
Just fear and hatred.
‎够了
Enough,
‎拜托！
please!
‎这个人背叛了科德温 ‎加入了猎魔人
This servant betrays Kaedwen to the witchers.
‎把她和那些人放到一起
Let her join them.
‎泰特拉！
Tetra!
‎你的人刀落一寸 ‎我就把他们都放倒
I can drop your men before their blades drop an inch.
‎想得美
Wishful thinking.
‎你还想好好过日子吗 ‎还是仍然因为那个大胆的除魔夜
Are you going to enjoy the day, or are you still too shook
‎而感到震惊呢？
from another daring night of monster-slaying?
‎原谅我只是不想做 ‎一个脾气暴躁的流氓
Pardon me for wanting to be something other than a churlish knave.
‎看看你啊
Look at you, though.
‎你是个猎魔人
You're a witcher.
‎你真有钱！
You're rich!
‎我们什么都不缺
We'll lack for nothing,
‎你要照顾我的 维瑟米尔
and you'll take care of me, Vesemir.
‎就像你说的那样
Much like you said.
‎兑现你的诺言
True to your word.
‎看着我！
-Look at me.
‎一间湖边小屋
-A lake house.
‎酒 食物
Wine. Food.
‎想象一下我们要沉入钱的海洋
Imagine the seas of coin we'd wade in.
‎你从来不想要那些！ ‎你总是很知足
You never wanted that! You were always content.
‎不！
No, no, no!
‎40吨羊血？
Forty tons of sheep's blood?
‎那个可怜的助产士！
That poor midwife!
‎跟他们说说你怎么骗了 ‎瑞达尼亚祭司
Oh, oh, tell 'em about the time you swindled the Redanian priest.
‎让他以为自己被诅咒了！
Had him thinking he was cursed!
‎-你骗了那个笨蛋多少钱？ ‎-你不可能在这里 我们已经失去了你
-How much did you take that fool for? -You can't be here. We lost you.
‎你在胡说什么？
What are you prattling about?
‎叫醒酒保 把酒喝干 ‎大家喝起来！
Wake the barkeep, drain the barrels. Everyone drink!
‎一毛不剩
Not a coin spared.
‎耶！
- Yeah! -
‎够了！
Enough!
‎所有人！
All of you!
‎别扯了！
Stop… stop cackling!
‎维瑟米尔 过来看看
Vesemir, come look.
‎现在说实话
Be honest, now.
‎那个 别光站在那里
Well, don't just stand there.
‎说出来吧
Say it.
‎你很讨厌这画 是吧？
You hate it, don't you?
‎我…
I…
‎我只是想确定 ‎你能不能画出我的翩翩风度
I was just weighing whether you'd done my dashing looks justice.
‎天啊
Oh, gods.
‎你吓到我了
You frightened me.
‎你的这个眼神 好气馁…
Such a look in your eyes. So crestfallen and…
‎很完美 伊利亚娜
It's perfect, Illyana.
‎完美无瑕
Flawless.
‎别磨蹭 我渴了
Don't dally. I'm thirsty.
‎妈妈！让博扬住手！
Mama! Make Bojan stop!
‎他拿了我的游戏跑走了！
He's run away with my jacks!
‎怎么了 爸爸？
What's wrong, Papa?
‎你的表情好悲伤
You're making the sad face.
‎不
No, no…
‎这是假的
This is wrong.
‎别再打心理仗了 小狐 别再用幻象
Enough mind games, Kitsu. No more fantasies.
‎但是你发过誓 ‎你会照顾我的 对吧？
But you swore you'd care for me, didn't you?
‎你会保护我
That you'd protect me.
‎你不是真的
You're not real.
‎真相不是幻象
Truth is no illusion.
‎不要逃避
There's no escaping it.
‎离我远一点！
Get away from me!
‎你把我留在这里 亲爱的
You left me here, darling.
‎被抛弃在希望和梦想中
Stranded in hopes and dreams abandoned.
‎现在又要再次离开我
And now you're trying to leave me again.
‎只是这次
Only this time,
‎我不会带着礼服 王庭和头衔 ‎被埋葬
I won't be buried -in dresses and courts and titles.
‎我会像你一样
I'll be as you are.
‎迷失和孤独
Lost and alone.
‎没人爱！
Unloved!
‎不 伊利亚娜 我爱你
No, Illyana. I love you.
‎钱才是你真正的情人
Coin's your real lover.
‎你的心里更多的是它 对吗？
More of her to pluck out there, isn't there?
‎别说了
Stop it.
‎我们可以像想象中一样 维瑟米尔
We can be whatever we imagine here, Vesemir.
‎我们可以发财
We can be rich.
‎一起
-Together.
‎在这里 时间不算什么
Here, time is nothing. -
‎在外面 我才能救她
Out there, I can save her.
‎那样才更值得
That's worth more.
‎现在 滚出我的脑海
Now, out of my head.
‎我知道你从没要求过这个
I know you never asked for this.
‎你只是个孩子
You were only a child.
‎你又怎么会知道？
How were you to know?
‎维瑟米尔！
Vesemir!
‎躲在后面！
Stay back!
‎你用魔法来攻击我？
You come at me with magic tricks?
‎不…
Oh, no…
‎不！
No! No!
No, no, no, no!
‎维瑟米尔！
Vesemir.
‎这…
This…
‎这不是真的
this isn't real.
‎我小时候对猎魔人不太了解
I didn't know much about witchers when I was young.
‎我不知道你们嗅觉更好 听力更好
I didn't know you could smell better, hear better.
‎我不知道那个猎魔人 ‎在橱柜里闻到了我
I didn't know that the witcher sensed me in the cupboard,
‎感觉到了我颤抖 几乎没有呼吸
trembling, barely breathing,
‎我看着他拿剑刺穿我妈妈
watching as he drove his sword through my mother.
‎那个愚蠢的女巫 ‎惹到了一个容易上当的祭司
The silly sorceress who'd crossed a gullible priest.
‎以怪制怪
Monsters to kill monsters.
‎哎…
Aye…
‎所以…
So…
‎带她走
Take her and go.
‎斯温？
Sven?
‎其他人呢？
The others?
‎死了
Dead.
‎我所有的人
All my boys.
‎除了你
-Save you.
‎年轻的孩子
- The young ones…
‎逃走了
-escaped. -
‎保持体力
Keep your strength.
‎他们现在是你的孩子了 小子
They're your boys now, young fella.
‎让他们成为猎魔人
Make 'em witchers.
‎让他们
Make 'em…
‎不仅如此
somethin' more.
‎变成更好的人
To better men.
‎这不是她主动要求的
She didn't ask for this.
‎我们在哪里？
Where are we?
‎真美
Beautiful.
‎看起来不像是真的
It doesn't seem… real.
‎我们知道要去哪儿吗？
-Do we even know where we're going? -
‎这是我最后一次允许大家犹豫
This is the last time I allow any of you to ever hesitate.
‎决定吧
Decide.
‎但是 他们讨厌我们
But they hate us.
‎总会出现新的怪物
There'll always be another monster…
‎杰洛特
Geralt.
‎（改编自安杰伊•萨普科夫斯基 ‎《猎魔人》系列）
‎曾有一位贵族
♪ There once was a lord ♪
‎进入幽暗森林
♪ In dark woods ♪
‎一条奇怪的
♪ Wearing a strange ♪
‎银色手带
♪ Silver band ♪
‎佩戴在
♪ Around ♪
‎手腕上
♪ His hand ♪
‎这条手带
♪ For the bandit also ♪
‎能够退却
♪ Feared ♪
‎怪物
♪ Monsters ♪